Guide to the Marjorie Knoll papers,1954-1999
Knoll, Marjorie papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Marjorie Knoll papers, 1954-1999
6787
Marjorie. Knoll
.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Publications, Photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, lectures, publications, awards, and photographs, documenting Knoll's involvement in AAFCS and her career as a home economist at Penn State University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Marjorie Knoll received her Bachelor of Science degree (1942) and Masters of Arts degree (1947) from the University of Nebraska and her Doctor of Philosophy degree (1954) from Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, lectures, publications, awards, and photographs, documenting Knoll's involvement in AAFCS and her career as a home economist at Penn State University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Knoll, Marjorie.; American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences; Pennsylvania State University.Dept. of Household Economics and Management.
Subjects:
Home Economics--Study and teaching
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Publication - "Comparison of 35 Home Management Programs with 10 NYS Programs" (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Publication - "Economic Contributions Given To and Received From Individual Members of Families and Households in Relation to their Financial Situations", 1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Publication - "Economic Contributions To and From Individual Members of Families and Households", 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Publication - "Using Research in Family Economics and Home Management in High School Teaching", 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Publication - "Household Work Contributions of Employed and Non-Employed Homemakers With and Without Children", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Publication - "Economic Contributions and Receipts of Household Members", October1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Publication - "A Two in One Course For Home Management Residence ", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Publication - "Teaching Home Managment and Furnishing Homes for Family Living", 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Publication - "Towards a Conceptual Framework in Home Management", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Publication - "Home Management Theory and Practice", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Publication - "French Lick -Twelve Years Later", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Lecture - "Family Management in the Next 50 Years", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lecture - "A Conceptual Framework For Home Management" Given At Maryland Home Ec Association, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lecture - "The Family and Decision Making", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Lecture - "Interaction of Family Focused Fields" Talk Given At Virginia H Ec Convention, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Lecture - "Teaching Home Management", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Lecture - "Interaction of Family Focused Fields", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Lecture - "Teaching Management", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Lecture By Telephone- "Trends in Research in Home Management" Given to Workshop in Michigan, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Lecture - "Family Economics- Home Management As An Interdisciplinary Phenomenon, Should FEHM Join?", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Lecture - "Home Management as a Field of Study", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Lecture At NCR 116- "Family Resource Management" Meeting, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Lecture - "Housing Alternatives", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Lecture - "Home Management As A Profession", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Lecture - "Responsible Decision Making: The Family's Imperative" Seoul, Korea, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Lecture - "Consumer Issues for the Retired", 1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Lecture - "Your Personal and Professional Resource" ,"Time: Friend or Foe", 1979, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Correspondence - "Concerning Home Management Issues", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- FEHM Seminar - "New Program For Home Management", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Survey - "Information for Home Management", 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- "Information Used for creating a Financial Check-Up" (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Lecture - "Challenges for the Eighties in Family Economic Home Management" Given at Southern Region, Kentucky, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Lecture PHEA- "Home Management: Retrospect and Prospect", 1981 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Lecture - "Implications of the Gross, Crandall, Knoll Conceptual Frameworks", 1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- "Information for Class Given At Penn State", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Note Concerning Kurt Back's Article - "Decisions Under Uncertainty", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Photograph - "Marjorie Knoll, Elizabeth Crabdall, Irma Gross", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- "AHEAF Distinguished Service Award to Liz Crandall" Supporting Documentation, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- "AHEAF Distinguished Service Award to Irma Gross" Supporting Documentation (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Newspaper Clippings - "Based on Knoll Research", 1955 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- "Awards", 1994- 1999 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Home Management Conferences: Penn State 1942; Michigan State 1955, 1942; 1955 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- "Distinguished Alumnus Award Presented to Dr. Marjorie Knoll by University of Nebraska, Lincoln", April 1994 (Box 1)
- "Kappa Omicron Nu Honor Award to Marjorie Knoll", 1994 (Box 1)